Neha Shah

@neha_shah www.nehashah.info github.com/owlbytes neshah07@gmail.com

Young professional interested in the intersection between people and technology. Varied experiences include web development, community management, client services, research, and social media. UK & USA citizen, with residency in Switzerland.

SKILLS

Programming Languages and Frameworks

- Ruby
- Rails
- Javascript
- SQL
- HTML5
- CSS

Developer Tools and Services

- Github
- Heroku
- Facebook SDK
- Mandrill
- Google Maps API
- Chrome Dev Tools

Software and Technical Applications

- Adobe Photoshop & Dreamweaver
- Google Analytics
- Sublime
- Terminal
- MS Office
- Trello

Methodologies

- Lean Startup
- Agile
- SCRUM
- Version Control

Foreign Languages

- German
- Spanish

PROJECTS

AeroSoul

http://aerosoul.me/

A web application that lets you discover and curate street art.

- Languages/Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, HTML5, CSS
- Features: carousel, Google Maps API, Google/Facebook OAuth, search, favoriting, tagging, voting.

Hoots

http://hoots-app.herokuapp.com/

Hoots allows users to write, promote, and vote on 141-character messages of positivity.

- Languages/Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, HTML5, CSS
- Features: Google/Facebook OAuth, search, favoriting, voting, texting posts (via Twilio).

Amy & Tina

http://amytina.herokuapp.com/

Amy & Tina allows users to discover advice from cultural icons Tina Fey and Amy Poehler.

- Languages/Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, HTML 5, CSS

EXPERIENCE

Big Bear Labs

Communications Lead, Zurich, Summer 2013

Responsible for communications, marketing, business operations, funding, and customer development for a technology startup.

Freelance Work Zurich, 2012-2013

- Wrote web copy and conducted content audits for an energy company, independent furniture designer, and a Middle Eastern poultry company.

- Researched and wrote daily security briefings on the Middle East.

Appulai

Marketing Intern, New York City, Fall 2011-Spring 2012

Marketing and public relations for launching iPhone/Android applications. Conducted product and market research. Monitored press coverage and assisted with media outreach.

- Managed social networks on behalf of clients.
- Created product and agency assets.

Bose

Contracted Inbound Sales Representative, Massachusetts, Spring/Summer 2011

Promoted the purchase of premium music systems, headphones, and home theater systems. Resolved customer service issues.

- Consistently among highest performing contractors with over \$29K in weekly sales, a 20% conversion rate (calls to sales) and 9.6% up sell rate.

Electronic Arts

Bioware Community Management/Marketing Intern, California, Summer 2009

Responsible for social media initiatives, including product launches and contests. Oversaw Twitter and Facebook day-to-day. Wrote reports on press coverage, social media activities, and the Bioware community.

- Conducted marketing research on competitive titles and the needs of the role-playing-game community, supporting the positioning of a new game for a successful launch.
- Created a video to showcase the EA intern experience.
- Designed a Facebook version of the game Road Rash as part of an intern game design competition.

On The Fly DC

Marketing Intern, Washington DC, Summer 2009

Created a marketing campaign to increase company visibility for a local eco-friendly food truck startup. Pursued public relations opportunities in the DC and business press.

Additional Experience

- Event Planner- National Association of Schools of Public Affairs & Administration (Fall 2009)
- Residential Assistant- The George Washington University (2008-2009)
- Marketing Intern- The New York Observer (2008-2009)
- Congressional Intern- Congressman David Wu (Spring 2008)
- Steering Committee Member- Amnesty International (2006-2008)

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Intensive, London, Fall 2013 Community Management, New York, March 2012 Setting Entrepreneurial Goals That Stick, New York, April 2012

Berlitz Language School

German, Fall 2012- Spring 2013

Inlingua International

Spanish, Fall 2011-Summer 2012

New Work City

Thinking Like a Programmer, February 2012

The George Washington University

BA International Affairs, 2012